Keep the lights on in your room and please watch from a distance.
[A cold is spreading at the Hostess Club. And, right when they are expecting an important customer...]
[The "GinTama" anime is being criticized. And, right when there's an episode like this...]
[Hostess Club Smile]
(店長)え？ 花子ちゃんも風邪？
Huh? You caught a cold, too, Hanako-chan?
(咳)
I'm sorry.
(花子)すんません…
熱は 微熱なんやけど➡
I have a low fever, and I can't stop coughing.
咳が止まらんくて… ｹﾎｹﾎ…｡
お客さんにうつしても あれやし｡
I don't want to pass it on to the customers.
(店長)あぁ わかった わかった｡
Ah, all right, all right. Just go home today and rest.
とにかく 今日は もう帰って
ゆっくり休んでよ｡
ﾎﾝﾏ すんません｡
I'm really sorry.
Make sure you wear a lot of warm clothes, drink lots of POCARI and sweat it out.
[Note: POCARI is a Japanese sports drink.]
厚着して ﾎﾟｶﾘいっぱい飲んで
いっぱい 汗かくんだよ｡
はい｡
微熱なめたら
怖いからね｡ お大事にね！
All right.
You'd better not underestimate a low fever! Take care of yourself.
(咳)
(店長)まずいね…｡
This is bad...
(黒服)まずいですね｡
(黒服)風邪蔓延… すっかり
葬式みたいになっちゃいましたね｡
The cold is spreading. The hostess club feels like a funeral.
(店長)明日は
大事な上客が 来るってのに…｡
And we host a VIP guest tomorrow...
(黒服)確か 幕府の重鎮とか…｡
As I recall, he's a very important Bakufu official.
(店長)まずいね｡
This is bad...
(黒服)まずいですね｡
いや ﾏｼﾞで まずいね｡
Well, this is really bad...
いや ﾏｼﾞで まずいですね｡
(店長)使えそうな子は
残ってないの？
Aren't there any girls available?
(黒服)あの… １人だけ｡
Well...
...just one...
(いびき)
["Rank Has Nothing to Do With Luck"]
まずいね｡
This is bad...
まずいですね｡
No, this is worse than you thought.
いや お前が思ってるより
まずいね｡
全然 まずいですね｡
No, this is way worse than you thought.
(黒服)しかし なんで
(いびき)
よりによって…｡
...But why of all people...
ﾊﾞｶは 風邪ひかないって… ｳｺﾞｯ…！
Well, it's said that an idiot can't catch a cold-
(店長)すいません… 明日 ﾎﾞｸ
休ませてもらえますか？
I'm sorry. May I take the day off tomorrow?
(お妙)白装束 着て
睡眠薬飲んで➡
Make sure you wear a white gown, take lots of sleeping pills and get enough sleep.
[Note: White clothes often symbolize death. She's suggesting he kill himself.]
いっぱい寝るんですよ｡
(店長)はい｡
All right.
女 ﾅﾒたら怖いですからね｡
You'd better not underestimate a woman, okay?
[THE NEXT DAY]
(銀時)恋は病
っていうだろうがよ｡
People say that love is a sickness.
(銀時)男を 恋わずらいに
侵すはずのｷｬﾊﾞ嬢が➡
The hostesses who make men lovesick all caught colds?
揃いも揃って 風邪ひくたぁ…
ﾌﾟﾛ意識のかけらもねえな！
You hostesses have no professional pride, bastards.
おめえらはよぉ この野郎！
それにしても お前は
やっぱ たいしたもんだなぁ｡
But you look fine. You look as healthy as always.
ﾋﾟﾝﾋﾟﾝしてるじゃねえか｡
やっぱ ﾊﾞｶは… ﾌﾞｵｯ!!
So it's true that an idiot-
やぁ 面目ない｡ ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢 １人じゃ➡
Well, it's a shame. But I can't open my club with just one hostess.
店を開くことも
ままならなくてね｡
なんとかならんかね？ 銀さん｡
Is there any way you can help us, Gin-san?
ｱﾝﾀ 万事屋だろ？
顔も広いじゃない｡
You're the owner of Odd Jobs, aren't you? So you must know a lot of people.
かわいい子の２～３人
すぐ紹介できるでしょ～！
It should be easy for you to introduce a couple of cute girls to us.
かわいい子がいるなら
ｵﾚが 紹介してほしいよ｡
If there were a pretty girl around, I'd introduce her to myself.
(神楽)かわいい子なら
ここに いるｱﾙよ｡
There's a pretty girl right here!
今夜は 松平公の知り合いの➡
Tonight we are hosting a top government official who is a friend of Matsudaira.
幕府のお偉いさんが
来ることになっててね｡
おい 無視してんじゃねえぞ｡
Hey, stop ignoring me.
It's a rare opportunity to get a prestigious customer like him.
こんな上客 つかめるﾁｬﾝｽ
めったにないのよ｡
報酬はずむから 頼むよ｡
おい ﾋｹﾞ こら！
I'll pay you generously, so please help us.
Hey, beard! Hey!
かわいい子かぁ
思い当たるふしがねえなぁ｡
Cute girls, hmm... No one pops up in my mind...
おい ここ！ 目を開けるね！
Hey, over here! Open your eyes!
探し物は すぐ近くにあるｱﾙよ！
What you're looking for is right next to you!
ﾂﾗは ともかく
性格が悪いのが多くてなぁ…｡
Aside from their looks, most of them are not nice... Ah, there's one.
ああ！ ｱｲﾂがいた！
そう ｱｲﾂ ｱｲﾂ！
Yes! This one, this one.
ああ やっぱﾀﾞﾒだ！
Well...no. If she doesn't have antennas and a psycho gun on her left arm...
[Note: Refers to a character from COBRA, a manga from the 80s.]
触覚と左手に仕込んだ
ｻｲｺｶﾞﾝさえなければなぁ…｡
誰あるか？ それぇ!?
ほとんど ﾊﾞｹﾓﾝだろうがよ～!!
Who is that?! Is she like a monster?!
Um... If it's all right, can I call up my friends? I know many pretty girls.
あの 私の友達でよければ
呼びましょうか？
かわいい子 いますよ｡
No. You can't trust a woman who says she knows "pretty women."
ﾀﾞﾒだ｡ 女の言う
かわいい子は 信用ならねえ！
だいたい 自分より
ﾗﾝｸ下のﾔﾂ 連れてくんだよ｡
She always brings girls who don't look as good as her.
(新八)銀さん なんか
嫌な思い出でもあるんですか？
Did you have some bad experiences with that, Gin-san?
(九兵衛)すいません… あの…➡
Excuse me.
Um... Is Tae-chan here? I've brought something for her.
妙ちゃんはおられるか？
差し入れを…｡
Ah...
(九兵衛)あの…｡
...Um...
ちょっと 何を…｡
Well... what...?
ｷｬｧｧｧ～！
おぉぉ～！
Kyu-chan, you're really cute!
九ちゃん かわいい！
いいよ これ！
This is great! This girl is fantastic!
すごい いいよ この子…｡
(東城)ｷｻﾏら～！
You bastard! What are you doing with our Young Lord?
若に何をしているかぁ!!
Wait. Calm down. We have a bit of a complicated situation here.
待て おちつけ
いろいろ わけがあってな｡
ちょっとだけだから
力貸してください すいまっせん！
Please help us out for a while. I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
ﾎﾝﾄ すいまっせん!!
ふざけるなっ!!
Give me a break! As you bastards already know...! Young Lord...
ｷｻﾏらも 知っているだろう！
若は… 若は➡
Young Lord...!
ｺﾞｽﾛﾘのほうが似合うぞ～っ!!
...would look much better wearing a Goth-Loli costume!
ｳｶﾞｯ!!
I don't know much about this, but if Tae-chan is in trouble, I will help.
(九兵衛)よくわからんが
妙ちゃんが困っているなら➡
ﾎﾞｸは 力を貸すぞ｡
(お妙)ごめんなさい 九ちゃん｡
I'm sorry to make you feel uncomfortable, Kyu-chan.
嫌な思いさせちゃって｡
いいんだ｡
うまくできるか わからんが➡
No problem. I'm not sure if I can handle this, but I'll give it a try.
やってみる｡
いけませんぞ 若!!
No, Young Lord!
ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢とは 見ず知らずの客と
ﾏｯﾄの上で 30分 １本勝負で…｡
A hostess engages in a 30-minute, one-round match
No. The place you go to isn't a hostess club.
違う｡ お前の通ってる店は
それ ｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗ違う！
with a strange customer... And it feels really nice...
行ってませんよ 若！
言っておきますが 私は➡
I didn't go, Young Lord!
I'm telling you, I didn't pay 10,000 yen for a one-time course! Please don't hate me.
１本 １万円ｺｰｽなんて
行ってませんからね！
嫌いにならないでね！
Don't worry. I've hated you all along.
心配するな｡ もとから嫌いだ｡
でも ﾎﾝﾄに大丈夫？ 九ちゃん…｡
But are you really okay with this, Kyu-chan?
今まで 男の子として生きてきた
九ちゃんが➡
You've lived as a man until now, and now you'll accompany men...
男の人の相手をするなんて｡
友人と話す感覚で
いけばいいのだろ？
It'll be just like talking with my friends, right?
会話は あれだが… なかには
ｹﾂとか触ってくるﾔﾂもいるぜ｡
Well, a conversation might be all right, but there're guys who'll slap your ass.
大丈夫か？
多少の恥なら我慢する｡
Are you fine with that?
I'll be patient but somewhat ashamed. I've caused you guys a lot of trouble before.
ｷﾐらには いろいろ 迷惑をかけた｡
少しでも力になりたい｡
So I want to help you as much as possible.
九ちゃん…｡
Kyu-chan...
じゃ… お言葉に甘えるが
あんまり ﾑﾘすんなよ｡
Well, if you're sure it's all right...but don't push yourself.
男でも女でも ｹﾂ触られりゃ➡
Regardless of whether you're a man or a woman,
it's natural to feel uncomfortable when someone touches your ass.
嫌がんのが
自然な反応ってもんだ｡
うおぉぉぉっ!!
ぎゃぁぁ!!
ﾌﾝ… 若に気安く触れると
そういう目にあいますよ｡
If you touch Young Lord in such a friendly manner, you'll get tossed like that.
若は 女の子は大好きですが➡
Young Lord likes young girls, but if some pathetic man touches her,
ﾑｻｲ男に触れられると
虫唾が走り➡
今のような行動に
出てしまうのです｡
it makes her skin crawl and she does what she just did now.
(九兵衛)やめろ その言い方｡
Stop talking like that.
You react like that even when someone just touches your shoulder.
肩に触れられた程度で
その始末のお人が➡
ﾏｯﾄの上で 客と勝負できますか？
Do you think you can really have a match with a customer on the mat?
だから 違うって言ってんだろ！
We already told you that's not it!
体じゅうに ﾛｰｼｮﾝ
塗りたくれば 平気だ！
If I rub lotion all over my body, they won't be able to do anything to me. They can't beat me!
技はかからない｡
だから違えって言ってんだろ！
I'm saying that's all wrong. Why are you talking about lotion pro-wresting?
なんで ﾛｰｼｮﾝﾌﾟﾛﾚｽなんだよ！
いいかげんにしなされ…｡
Please stop this already.
It's about time we head back or we'll miss the rerun of Hachikuro.
[Note: Hachikuro (Honey and Clover) is a TV show/anime.]
そろそろ戻らねば
『ﾊﾁｸﾛ』の再放送が…｡
さっ 帰りましょう｡
(雄叫び)
Let's go home.
(悲鳴)
I am Ayumu Tojo! My life's mission is to protect the Young Lord!
わかり申した！
この東城 歩…
若の御身を守るが 生涯の務め！
私も ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢になって
若を最後まで守り通します！
So, I'll become a hostess and protect Young Lord to the end!
とりあえず なんやかんやで
３人まで揃ったな｡
Well, at this point, we somehow have three...
No, we don't. And I think one person is a complete mismatch.
揃ってませんよ… つうか➡
１人 完全に
間違ってる人がいるんですけど｡
Why does he have a towel wrapped around himself?
何だ？ あのﾀｵﾙの巻き方…
なんで胸 隠してんだ？
Why is he hiding his chest? That really pisses me off.
すんげえ 腹立つんだけど！
How many more people do you need?
あと 何人くらい必要なんだ？
最低でも あと３人は欲しいね｡
I need at least three more.
(神楽)私 入れたら あと２人ｱﾙな｡
If you count me in, we need only two more.
あと３人か… だりいな｡
おい あと２人だって｡
Three more... That'll be more work.
Hey, only two more.
誰かいないの？ もう
かわいきゃいいからさ｡
Don't you know anyone? Anyone's all right, as long as she's good-looking.
おい 聞けよ 泣くぞ｡
Hey, listen to me. Or I'll cry.
I already talked to one girl, so it'll work.
１人は もう 話 つけてあるから
何とかなるとして…｡
Damn it. Forget it.
あぁ もう呼んでるの
さすが万事屋！
Ah, you already called her. That's great, Odd Jobs.
(ｷｬｻﾘﾝ)こんにちは！
Hello there. I came here because I heard I could get free sake!
ただ酒 飲めるって
聞いて来ました｡
人の話 聞いてた？
Did you hear what I said?!
引き立て役だ… ｸﾞﾙｰﾌﾟの場合
ああいうのも必要なんだよ｡
She'll serve as a foil. In a group, someone like her is essential.
ｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞ しかり ﾓｰ娘｡ しかり！
It's like SPEED, or Momusu. Whatever.
[Note: SPEED and Momusu (short for Morning Musume) are all-female J-pop groups.]
なんか いんだろ？
途中から 完全に➡
It's going completely haywire! Why are you wrapped in a towel, too?!
流れがおかしいだろ！ つうか➡
なんで お前までﾀｵﾙ巻いてんの？
It's a service to TV viewers, of course.
視聴者ｻｰﾋﾞｽに決まってんだろ！
For now, give me ten million yen as my performance fee!
とりあえず ｷﾞｬﾗ １千万円
よこせよ ｺﾗ！
(店長)顔だけじゃなく
性格も最悪なんだけど｡
Not only is she lacking in the looks department, but her personality is the worst.
あと２人ねぇ…｡
Two more...
Hey! What?! From the ceiling?
(店長)ちょっと なに？
天井から！
おい… 立て ｺﾗ ｽﾄｰｶｰ｡
Hey, you.
Stand up, Stalker. Starting today, you're a hostess, too.
今日から お前もｷｬﾊﾞ嬢だ｡
(さっちゃん)触らないで！
触ってねえよ｡
Don't touch me!
I didn't!
柳生編だか なんだか
知らないけど➡
I don't know anything about the Yagyu Arc or anything else.
さんざん 長いこと放置ﾌﾟﾚｲして➡
But you left me alone for a long time, and I finally spotted you in the previous episode.
久しぶりに 前回
会えたと思ったら➡
And now you're asking me to work as a hostess? That...
今度は ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢になれ!? そんな…｡
そんなのって…｡
That...
興奮するじゃないのぉ！
...makes me so fired up.
You know exactly how to get me all excited!
どれだけ 私のﾂﾎﾞを
心得てるのよぉっ！
(店長)いや ｱﾝﾀも 思いきり
間違ってるんだけど…｡
Well... You're also a mismatch.
かわいいから いいか…
もう 嬢 しか合ってないよ｡
But that's okay, as long as you're good-looking.
Really, I don't know what kind of group this is, except that they all look like girls.
これ なんの集団？
Fine. There're six here.
よし これで ６人揃ったな｡
Oh? I only count five. We're one short.
えっ まだ５人…
１人 足りませんよ？
おい！
Hey...
酒は飲むなよ…
ｵﾛﾅﾐﾝCまでなら 勘弁してやる｡
Don't drink. You can drink Koronamin-C, though.
[Note: Parody of Oronamin-C, a carbonated beverage.]
銀ちゃぁん！
Gin-chan...
(店長)ここは 化け物屋敷？
Is this a monster house?!
Manager! Our guest has arrived.
(黒服)店長！ お客様 来ました!!
Eh? Already? What should we do?
えっ もう？ どうしよう！
みんな 早く出迎えに！
Everyone, hurry! Let's go greet him!
お水の花道は もう
始まっているのよ！
The glorious path of the hostesses has begun.
(神楽たち)はい！
All right!
大丈夫かねぇ…｡
やれるさ｡
Can they handle it?
They'll be all right. They will...
ﾔﾂらなら…｡
Hey... Hurry and get up there.
ちょっと 早く上がれって！
ﾛｰｼｮﾝが滑って…｡
The lotion's making me slip...
Hey! What are you doing?!
おいぃい！ なにしてんだぁっ!?
Before they even got to see any customers, they croaked on the job!
(店長)客に会う前に
いきなり殉職しちゃったよ！
しっかりしろ おい！
なにしにきたんだ お前ら!!
Come on! Hey! What was your reason for even coming here?!
ｼﾞｬﾏ者以外の 何者でもねえよ！
You've doing nothing but cause trouble!
とりあえず片付けるぞ｡
For now, let's clean up.
不自然だ… こんなもん
転がってたら！
It looks unnatural to leave these guys on the floor.
気をつけてよ…
ｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙだから ｺｲﾂら｡
Be careful! These guys are really slippery! Watch your step!
足元 気をつけて… うわぁっ！
(新八/銀時)てっ… 店長！
Ma-Manager!
み… 店を… 頼む…｡
Take...care of... my club...
店長～！
Manager!!
とりあえず 片付けるぞ 店長も｡
Let's clean him up, too.
So fast! That was a quick change of heart!
はやっ！ 切り替え はやっ!!
What? I don't see many hostesses here tonight. We can't go crazy with this.
(松平)なんだい？ 今日は
店の子 少なくねえか？
盛り上がらねえな これじゃ…｡
(お妙)大丈夫ですよ…
あちらに行けば➡
Don't worry. There'll be plenty more once we get there.
いっぱい いますから…｡
《銀時/新八:きた！》
They're coming!
What should we do now? She said there'd be "plenty."
どうするんですか！
いっぱい いるとか
言っちゃってますよ！
We've gotta do something right now!
早くしないと！
Ah, what are you guys doing? Hurry up and come over here.
なにやってんだ？ お前ら！
はよ こい!!
See, Matsudaira-san, everybody's waiting for you.
あっ ほら 松平さん…
みんな 待ってますよ｡
どうも… ﾊﾟｰ子でぇす！
ﾊﾟﾁ恵でぇす！
Hello! I'm Pako.
I'm Pachie.
So why are you guys wrapped in towels?!
《だから なんで
ﾀｵﾙ 巻いてんのぉ！》
《銀時/新八:着替える時間が
なかったんじゃあ！》
We didn't have time to change!
(近藤)あれ？ 今日
初めて見る子が 多いな｡
Huh?
I see many new faces today. Are they all new?
新人さん？
《銀時/新八:ぐっ… げぇ～っ！》
♪♪～
[Hostess Club Smile]
Wh-Why...?!
《新八/銀時:なっ… なんでぇ!?》
《よりによって 真選組が…｡
Of all people, why are the Shinsengumi, the top people in the government, here?!
幕府のお偉いさんが
来るんじゃあ！
まずいぞ…
あの人たちが相手じゃ➡
Ah, what are you guys doing?! I didn't know you were interested in such things...
This is bad. If they're our guests...we have to not only attend...
接客どころか もう通りを
大手を振って歩けない！
We can't walk with our heads held high... Gin-san! What should we do?!
銀さん… どうしよう！》
いらっしゃいませ～｡
Welcome!
《銀さん～っ！ まさか➡
Gin-san!
Don't tell me...! Does he think he's well disguised?
変装してるつもりなのか？
What is he trying to do with that?
やるつもりなのか？ それで…》
Stick out your chin and mumble, Pachie. Mumble softly.
しゃくれ ﾊﾟﾁ恵…
軽く しゃくっとけ｡
しゃくっとけば ばれねえって
ﾃﾚﾋﾞで 大地 真央が言ってた｡
Mao Daichi said on TV that if you mumble, no one would recognize you.
[Note: Mao Daichi is a musical star actress.]
《ﾑﾘﾑﾘ ばれるって…
そんなもん➡
No way! They'll find out...
It's like putting on a black tank top and briefs and saying "I'm Death."
ﾌﾞﾘｰﾌに黒いﾀﾝｸﾄｯﾌﾟ着て➡
｢死神です｣と
言うようなもんだよ！
Kagura-chan, can you say something to this idiot?
神楽ちゃん このﾊﾞｶに
なんとか言ってくれ！》
I'm Gurako. It's nice to meet you, bastard.
[Note: Kagura is imitating Antonio Inoki, who is known for his turned-up chin.]
ｸﾞﾗ子です よろしくお願いします
この野郎！
《もうやってるよ
しゃくっちゃってるよ この子！》
She already did it! She's mumbling! This girl...!
My hobby is shooting sixteen times with automatic fire.
趣味は 16連射です｡
Huh? Hey, Kyubei-san?
《あれ… ちょっ 九兵衛さん！》
趣味は ｽﾀｰｿﾙｼﾞｬｰです｡
My hobby is Star Soldier.
[Note: Star Soldier is a series of shoot'em up video games.]
Hey, don't copy the way she speaks! What kind of hostess club is this?!
《おい！ それを ﾏﾈすんな!!
どんなｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗだ！
しゃくれﾊﾞｰか！ ここは｡
Is this a club where everyone mumbles?
だから お前は
根本的に間違ってんの！
I already told you that you completely misunderstood the situation!
なんで安来節!?》
Why is she doing Yasugibushi?
[Note: Yasugibushi is a local folk song of the Shimane prefecture.]
(沖田)おい
いいﾒｽﾌﾞﾀがいるじゃねえか｡
Hey, I see some good masochism here.
《おい ｻﾄﾞ心に 火つけちまったよ｡
Hey, the sadist part of him awakened!
Hey, lady, I can put something much better than toothpicks up your nose.
お前ら 頼むから この店から
出ていけ！ 金 払うから!!》
Please get out of this club! I don't mind paying you for that!
[Don't get so cocky!
You white-assed brat.
Come back when your hair down there becomes a natural perm.
Then we'll talk.]
You're really something.
言うじゃねえか！
《なんで 通じてんだよ》
How could he even understand what she said?
(土方)おい 総悟 その辺にしとけ｡
Hey, Sogo, you'd better stop now.
We didn't come here today for fun.
今日は ｵﾚたちは
遊びにきたんじゃねえんだぞ｡
(松平)よぉ なんだよ…
遠慮すんなって ｵﾒｴらも飲んでけ｡
Yo, what's up? There's no need to hesitate. Have some drinks.
(土方)いや そうもいかねえ｡
No, we can't do that.
What? They didn't come here for drinks?
《なに？ 飲みにきたんじゃ
ないのか この人ら｡
助かった… えっ でも じゃあ
何しに来たんだ？ この人たち》
That's a relief! Huh? Hold on... Then why did they come?
(沖田)じゃあ ごゆっくり
楽しんでいってくだせえ｡
Well, please enjoy your time here. We'll be outside standing guard...
ｵﾚたちは しっかり
外 見張っとくんで…｡
(沖田)上様…｡
...my Lord...
♪♪～
銀さん 今
上様って聞こえませんでした？
Gin-san, did you just hear him say, "my Lord"?
聞こえたなぁ… いやでも まさか｡
Yeah. No... but it can't be...
ねぇ 今 上様って…｡
(お妙)んなわけないでしょ｡
Hey, he just said "my Lord."
There's no way something like that could have happened.
どうして天下の将軍様が
こんなｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗに来るの？
Why would Shogun-sama come to a hostess club like this?
さぁ どうぞ 上様 こちらです｡
Well, please come in, my Lord.
いや 今 お前も
上様って言ったろ！
Hey, you just called him "my Lord," too.
(神楽)
上様なんて よくある名前ｱﾙ｡
My Lord is a very common name.
[Note: In Japanese the term uesama means "my lord" and is often written on receipts to show respect for the customer.]
領収書なんて ほとんど上様ね｡
People always use that name on their receipt.
いや でも…｡
Well, but...
Did you just hear him wrong? Something like Uesugi-san?
(九兵衛)上杉さんとか
聞き間違えたのではないか？
(さっちゃん)ﾌｶﾞﾌｶﾞ…｡
それもそうだなぁ｡
Well, that's true. There's no way the Shogun would come here.
将軍が まさか こんなところに
来るわけねえもんな！
(松平)よぉ 将ちゃんったら
こっち こっち！
Yo, Sho-chan! Over here!
ほら 将ちゃんとか
呼ばれてるもん｡
See. He's even called Sho-chan.
かわいい あだ名ですわ
将ちゃんって…｡
Sho-chan is a cute nickname.
でも 本名のほうも
教えてくださいな｡
But tell me your real name. I'm just curious.
私 知りたいわ｡
(徳川)征夷大将軍 徳川 茂茂｡
The Seii Taishogun, Shigeshige Tokugawa.
[Note: Shogun is the shortened form of the title Seii Taishogun.]
Since I'm the Shogun, call me Sho-chan.
将軍だから 将ちゃんでいい｡
(お妙)いやだぁ
ご冗談が お上手な方ですね｡
Come on. You like telling jokes, don't you? What do you do for a living?
(お妙)お仕事は
何をなさっているんですか？
I just said I'm the Seii Taishogun.
(徳川)だから 征夷大将軍だ｡
(お妙)もう てんどんですか！
ﾎﾝﾄ おもしろい方ですね｡
Wow! Tendon? You're such a funny man.
[Note: In Japanese comedy, saying the same joke twice is called a "Tendon."]
(近藤)二番隊 三番隊は
裏をかためろ！
The second squad and third squad go way back!
♪♪～
(ﾍﾘｺﾌﾟﾀｰの音)
Listen up. Don't let even a mouse through!
(近藤)
いいか！ ﾈｽﾞﾐ１匹 通すなよ！
(近藤)たとえ
隕石が落ちてこようが➡
Even if a meteor falls from the sky...
上様を お守りするのだ！
...we'll protect our Lord!
♪♪～
(土方)しかし とっつぁんにも
困ったもんだぜ｡
But, really, this is a lot of work with our Lord here.
将軍に夜遊び ご教授たぁ
毎度毎度 警備に駆り出される➡
The Shogun is being schooled on how to have a great night life.
Every time he does that, we're the ones who have to guard him.
ｵﾚたちの身にも
なってほしいもんだ｡
I hope he understands how we feel.
とっつぁんも
城に ひきこもりっきりの上様に➡
Our Lord is always cooped up in his castle,
外の空気を
吸わせてやりたいのだろう｡
so our boss wants him to breathe some fresh air.
(近藤)お父上が
お亡くなりになって以来➡
Ever since our Lord's father passed away, our boss has been his substitute father.
とっつぁんは
上様の親父代わりになったと聞く｡
(土方)どこの世界に
息子とｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗに来る親父がいる？
Where on earth...
...is there a father who takes his son to a hostess club?
(近藤)ﾊﾊﾊｯ！
親父というより悪友かもな!!
Well, he's more a bad influence than a father.
男ってﾔﾂには ｳﾝ千万の家臣より➡
A man needs only one bad influence rather than thousands of followers.
たった一人の悪友が必要なのさ｡
ということで ﾄｼ！ 一緒に戻って
お妙さんと飲まんか？
Therefore, Toshi... Why don't we go in and have some drinks with Otae-san?
ｵﾚには そんな悪友いらねえ！
I don't need that kind of bad influence.
本物だぁ～!!
He's the real one! He's every inch the Seii Taishogun!
正真正銘
本物の征夷大将軍ですよ～！
どうすんですかぁ～!!
What we should do?!
と と… 取り乱すんじゃねえ
落ち着け!!
Don't lose your cool! Calm down! For now, let's get his autograph.
とりあえず ｻｲﾝもらおう!!
あっ 色紙ない！
Ah, we don't have a square card! Can we use this mat? It'll work, right?
ﾏｯﾄでいいかな？ いいよね！
ｱﾝﾀが落ち着け!!
You're the one who needs to calm down!
将軍の前に こんなｽﾞﾙｽﾞﾙのﾏｯﾄ
差し出せるか！
There's no way we can give this slippery mat to the Shogun!
落ち着いて聞け ﾊﾟﾁ恵｡
Calm down and listen, Pachie!
今回の仕事 うまくいきゃ
とんでもねえ大金が手に入るぞ！
If we handle this job, we'll get big money!
だが そのぶん ﾘｽｸもでけえ！
But, on the other hand, there'll be high risk, too!
粗相をしでかせば
首も とびかねねえ！
You know, if we do anything careless, we may lose our heads!
だから ｱﾝﾀが落ち着けって！
どんだけ 金 欲しいんですか!!
I just said calm down. Are you only after the money?!
(お妙)ささ もう１杯どうぞ｡
(松平)こりゃ まいった ｵﾗｵﾗｵﾗ…｡
Here we go. Another cup of sake.
幸い 鈍い女どもは
この事実に気づいてねえ｡
Fortunately, those dull girls don't realize the truth.
ﾔﾂらには
将軍のこと 一切しゃべるな！
Don't say anything about the Shogun.
動揺を招いて 必ず失敗する！
ここは冷静に…｡
It'll upset them and we'll fail. We need to calm down, and-
(松平)お～い しゃくれ女
ちょっと来いや！
Hey, you, the mumbling woman, come over here!
誰が しゃくれ女だ！
What's wrong with the mumbling girl?
女はな ちょっと
斜に構えてるくらいが➡
A woman with a little secret is the best!
いちばん かわいいんだって！
おい 冷静に 冷静に!!
Hey, calm down! Calm down!
(松平)そこの 廃校寸前の
学校にいそうな ｲﾓい おさげ！
Hey, you over there with the pigtails, the person who looks like she's from a school that's going to close!
お前も来い！
おさげ ﾅﾒんな～!!
You come here, too!
Don't underestimate pigtails!
一見 ｲﾓくて
ｸﾗｽでも目立たないが➡
At first glance, she looks a bit clunky, and nobody pays attention to her in class.
磨けば きれいになるんじゃね？
みたいな原石美人が➡
But with a little polish she'll become pretty. A man likes that kind of woman!
男は大好きなんだ～！
落ち着け 新八!!
Calm down, Shinpachi!
お前は磨いても 自転車の
錆びたﾍﾞﾙとかしか出てこなそう！
Even if you were polished, you'd be like the bell of a rusty bike!
(松平)う～ん…
これで人数も いい感じだな｡
Hmm... Looks like we have enough people now.
《耐えろよ…》
《ｱﾝﾀこそ…》
Be patient.
You, too.
(松平)え～ 酔いもまわってきたし
じゃあ そろそろ…➡
Well, I'm getting drunk, so it's about time to...
将軍様ｹﾞｰﾑ おっぱじめるよ～!!
...start the Shogun-sama game!
(ﾗｯﾊﾟ)
将軍様ｹﾞｰﾑ？
Shogun-sama game?
(松平)
説明しよう… 将軍様ｹﾞｰﾑとは➡
Let me explain the rules.
The Shogun-sama game
将軍と番号を書いたくじを
割り箸で作り➡
starts with writing numbers and the name "Shogun" on wooden chopsticks.
将軍と書かれたくじを
引き当てた者が➡
The one who draws the stick with "Shogun" on it
他の者に
さまざまな いやらしい命令➡
can give dirty commands to another person, who can't refuse.
かっこ 拒否不可 を
下すことができる➡
It's a game for adults only. Or it's like a king game.
大人のｹﾞｰﾑというか王様ｹﾞｰﾑである｡
もう 松平さんったら➡
Ah-ha, Matsudaira-san,
また ｹﾞｰﾑにかこつけて
ｴｯﾁなことするつもりですね？
you're using this game to cover up the fact that you're doing something dirty, right?
いやいや ｵﾚは 今回は
進行役で いかせてもらおう｡
No, no. I'll just be a facilitator this time. Well, young people can have fun.
まぁ 若いﾔﾂらで楽しめや｡
将軍様 引き当てるのは誰かな？
Let's see who gets the Shogun-sama stick!
《いや っていうか
将軍様いるんだけど…》
Well... I mean...
Shogun-sama is right here...
よ～し じゃあ 始めるぞ！
All right, let's begin. Draw a stick. First come, first-served...
ほら 早いもん勝ちで
くじ引き抜く… あぁ～っ！
はぁ～っ！
ふんっ…！
(神楽たち)うぉぉぉ～っ!!
(松平)どわ～っ!!
(衝撃音)
♪♪～
《ﾏｼﾞなんだけど…｡
Really... They have no intention of entertaining the customers.
客を 楽しませる気 ｾﾞﾛなんだけど｡
自分の欲望のことしか
頭に ないんだけど ｺｲﾂら！》
They're just focused on their own desires.
But this is a big chance, Pachie.
だ～が これは ﾁｬﾝｽだぞ ﾊﾟﾁ恵｡
If we let the real Shogun become the Shogun in the game, he'll thoroughly enjoy it.
将軍に
将軍様に なってもらって➡
ｹﾞｰﾑを 思う存分
楽しんでもらえば…｡
わかってますよ ﾊﾟｰ子さん｡
I know, Pako-san.
あ～あ 待ってください｡
もう ｸｼﾞが ﾒﾁｬｸﾁｬ！
Oh, my!
Hold on a second. The sticks are a real mess now.
しようがないな｡
じゃあ 私が ｸｼﾞを持つから➡
Oh, well, I'll hold the sticks, so everyone get over here when I give the signal.
みんな せ～の で 来てください｡
せ～の～!!
Start!
Shogun, pick the right one!
将軍 引けぇぇ～っ!!
《くっ…！ なに～っ!?
What?!
ﾁｯ！ 速い!!》
Tsk. Too fast!
将軍棒は… どこ!?
The Shogun stick... Who has it?
あ～ 私 将軍だわ｡
Ah, I'm the Shogun!
ﾊﾟｰ子さん！
Pako-san...
He's great! He sensed everyone's movements and picked the Shogun stick.
《さすが！
みんなの気配を 察知し➡
誰よりも早く 将軍棒を…｡
でも
ﾊﾟｰ子さんが将軍じゃ 意味が…！》
But if Pako-san is the Shogun, it's not going to work.
Let's see... the person who picked number 4, strip down to your underwear.
え～っと じゃあ ４番 引いた人➡
下着に なってもらえます～？
I see! This order will make everyone visually entertained, not just Shogun-sama.
《そうか！ この命令であれば
将軍様でなかろうと➡
視覚的に
楽しませることが できる！
What a great idea!
さすがだ！
Shogun-sama was the one?!
将軍かよ～！》
《将軍かよ～！》
This is bad. Why did he draw number 4, stupid Lord?!
やべえよ… なんで
４番 引いてんだよ あの ﾊﾞｶ殿｡
やべえよ…
怒ってるよ あれ 絶対…｡
This is really bad. He's definitely upset.
Please forgive me. I didn't mean to do it.
勘弁してくれよ…｡
悪気は なかったんだよ…｡
And on this day he happens to be wearing briefs. That just adds to his shame!
しかも よりによって
もっさりﾌﾞﾘｰﾌの日に➡
当たっちまったよ｡
恥の上塗りだよ～！
将軍家は 代々
もっさりﾌﾞﾘｰﾌ派だ！
The Shogun family traditionally wears manly briefs.
やべえよ～ 聞こえてたよ｡
しかも➡
This is really bad. He heard me. And he even said that he wears those every day!
毎日 もっさりﾗｲﾌだよ～！
Anyway, we have to get him dressed and out of that underwear situation. Or we'll be exiled.
とにかく 早く あのﾊﾟﾝﾂ姿から
元に戻してあげないと➡
島流しですよ…｡
お前か ｵﾚ➡
Either you or me must get the Shogun stick and-
どっちか 将軍に…｡
(さっちゃん)ぐあっ…！
Whoa! I lost again.
(神楽)うわっ！ また ﾊｽﾞﾚｱﾙ～！
ちょっと～！ なに 勝手に
２回戦 始めてんの～!!
Hey! Why did you start the second round on your own?!
I got it! I'm the Shogun!
やった～！ 私が 将軍よ～！
ｺｲﾂら
もう 完全に ｹﾞｰﾑ楽しんでるよ！
These guys are just enjoying the game!
将軍 おかまいなしだよ！
They don't care about the Shogun!
Well, let me see...
う～んと どうしようかなぁ｡
じゃあ 私は…➡
Then my order is...
３番の人が この場で
いちばん寒そうな人に➡
Number 3, give the person who looks the coldest your kimono.
着物を 貸してあげる｡
《姉上…》
...Sis...
Sis! You're great! You really care about the customers first!
《姉上～！ さすがです！
なんやかんやで お客さんのことを
いちばんに 考えてたんですね！
ﾌﾟﾛだよ！ ｱﾝﾀこそ ﾌﾟﾛ～!!
You're a professional! You're a true pro!
将軍かよ～！》
《将軍かよ～！》
Shogun, again?!
This is bad. It's been blurred out!
やべえよ ﾓｻﾞｲｸだよ…｡
And the Shogun's not a Shogun. It's like a foot soldier's size!
しかも 将軍 あっちのほうは
将軍じゃねえよ｡ 足軽だよ～｡
将軍家は 代々
あっちのほうは 足軽だ！
The Shogun family has traditionally been the size of a foot soldier.
Damn it. He heard me. We'll definitely be beheaded now.
やべえよ～ 聞こえてたよ～！
もう 確実に 打ち首獄門だよ！
Pachie, let's give up on all the kimonos whatsoever.
ﾊﾟﾁ恵… 着物云々は あきらめよう｡
見たとおり 失うもんは
もう 何もねえ！
As we can see, there's nothing to lose.
It can't get any worse than this. Things can only get better.
これ以下は ねえんだ｡
あとは 上がってくだけだ！
Hey...
(さっちゃん)ちょっと…｡
これ 臭いから➡
This is really stinky, so can I take it off?
脱いでいいかしら？
下 あったよ！
There is something worse...
ちょっと～
涙目に なってますよ 将軍…｡
Oh-oh! Shogun has grown teary-eyed. Is he crying? He's crying, isn't he?
泣いてるよね？
泣いてるんだよね？ あれ！
Hey, hey, hey! This is bad! It's like he's getting bullied!
おいおい おいおい やべえよ｡
なんか もう ただの ｲｼﾞﾒみたいに
なってきてんじゃねえかよ｡
I remember somebody who cried just like that in my class!
いたよ…
ｸﾗｽに こういう泣き方 するﾔﾂ！
このままじゃ やば…｡
(衝撃音)
This game is getting really bad...
ｱｲﾂら また…！
Those girls...!
Finally, my time has come. I have only one desire...for Gin-san to have se-
ついに 私の時代が きたわ｡
私の願いは １つ！
銀さんと ｾｯ…！
番号で言え ﾎﾞｹ～!!
Use the numbers, fool!
You hurt me, Otae-san.
痛いわね お妙さ～ん!!
Do you think you can get away with doing that to the Shogun?
将軍に こんなことして
ただで済むと 思ってるの!?
覚えてなさ～い!!
やってみろよ ｺﾗ｡
I'll remember this!
Try it if you can!
ﾄﾗﾝｸｽを…➡
Boxers... Number 5, go buy some boxers.
５番の人は
ﾄﾗﾝｸｽを 買ってきなさい｡
《さっちゃんさん… ｱﾝﾀ まさか➡
Sachan-san... You... could it be... You're doing this for the Shogun?
将軍のために…》
《２人:やっぱ 将軍かよ～！》
As we thought...the Shogun, again!
(近藤)上様…
今頃 楽しんでおられるだろうか？
Our Lord... I wonder if he's having a great time right now.
さあな｡
お妙さんに惚れてないといいが…｡
Who knows...
I hope he didn't fall in love with Otae-san.
(土方/近藤)うわっ…!?
(近藤)上様～!!
My Lord!
何を されてるんですか
そんな格好で～!!
Why are you naked?!
(近藤)あっ 上様～!?
Ah, my Lord.
やべえ！
えらいことに なってきた!!
Damn it. Things are getting even worse.
ｷｻﾏら 上様に 何をした～!!
You bastard! What did you do to our Lord?!
総員に 告ぐ！ 上様を 追え～!!
Attention everyone! Follow our Lord!
♪♪～
ｷｬｰｯ!!
Hey, wait!
おい！ 待てって！
Quickly draw!
早く 引くｱﾙ！
You guys are still doing that? You better stop it!
ｵﾒｴら まだ やってんのか!?
いいかげんにしろ！
♪♪～
[SHOGUN]
(神楽)将軍様！
我らに なんなりと ご命令を！
Shogun-sama, give us a command, anything you want.
♪♪～
(隊士)局長～！
Chief!
The hostesses are headed this way!
(隊士)ｷｬﾊﾞ嬢が
こちらに 向かって…！
(神楽たち)うぉぉぉ～っ!!
(爆発音と 悲鳴)
[Oedo Mart]
♪♪～
(九兵衛)上様…｡
My Lord...
お下着のほう お持ちしました｡
I brought underwear.
あの… いろいろ 失礼なこと…｡
...Um...about all the rude things we did...
(徳川)いいんだ…｡
That's all right.
楽しかったよ…｡
I had fun.
また ｢片栗虎｣にも
連れてきてもらうぞ｡
I'll ask Katakuriko to take me there again. So can you play with me again?
そのときは また 余と遊んで…｡
(九兵衛)うわぁ～っ!!
Do you know the origin of the word "hard-boiled?"
[Preview]
It comes from hard-boiled eggs. Right...
The moon tonight looks "hard-boiled."
Master... I'll have a Camus on the rocks.
[Note: Camus is a brand of Cognac.]
The next episode... "Hard-boiled Egg on a Man's Heart."
[Hard-boiled detective... Heiji Kozenigata]
[The legendary thief, Chogoro the Foxfire. A fateful confrontation with him?!]
Hard-boiled Detective is coming up next.